Edson Arturo Rodríguez Govea

Colima, México (CST) - <u>erodstardev@gmail.com</u> <u>Linkedin profile · GitHub · Portfolio</u>

I am a fullstack developer experienced on web applications handling technologies like Vue.js and React.js. I'm a person who loves to learn something new and create simple and complex web pages for process and/or problem improvement.

EXPERIENCE

DEC. 2023 – CURRENT FULLSTACK DEVELOPER, ITJ

I worked as a fullstack developer at this consultancy for the client "XiltriX", using React, TypeScript, Node, Redux, and other technologies to handle a device monitoring website.

- Created a new project from scratch based on a legacy project that the company had integrating new technologies based on the new tendencies of the software development.
- Integrated a map module using Leaflet.js to visualize and to add pieces of equipment to a blueprint previously updated by the users.
- Integrated the "Test Driven Development" (TDD) methodology to create different modules and functionalities based on the user stories requested by our managers.
- Helped to build the logic for the communication of the frontend and the backend using "Socket.io" to retrieve real time data from AWS.
- Integrated the "TanStack Query" library in order to enhance the way the state of the http requests and promises are handled in the frontend using also the ability of this library to store data on the cache of the website to make the user experience more faster managing a stale time of this data that automatically refresh after an established period of time.
- Helped to create and maintain different endpoints on the backend using the guidelines of nest.js creating custom "guards" to validate user roles, authentication and more. Also implemented the TypeORM integration to do mutations to the database built in PostgreSQL.

Technologies implemented: HTML, CSS, JS, React.js (v18, v19) · TypeScript · Vite · Vitest · Tailwind CSS · shadcn · Redux.js · Axios · Leaflet.js · TanStack Query · Nest.js · TypeORM · PostgreSQL

NOV. 2022 – OCT. 2023 FULLSTACK DEVELOPER, SONATAFY

Management and update of the customer administrative tools, based on automated tests and agile communications between systems.

 Improvement on the client administrative website both on usability and troubleshooting implementing automated tests.

- Contribution to a better planning for the data management architecture from the backend.
- Development of a custom component library from scratch for the client using Vue2 (Options API), taking as reference the most popular ones on the market such as Buefy or Vuetify, focusing on the needs and preferences of the client.
- Creation of endpoints through Node.js consuming information from both GraphQ and a MySQL database.
- Creation of Lambda functions using Node.js to be able to be consumed through the Hasura platform, in what is known as HASURA actions.

Technologies implemented: Vue.js, Jest, Cypress, Node.js, AWS, GraphQL, PostgresSQL, Git, Github.

NOV. 2021 - NOV. 2022

MOBILE TEAM LEAD DEVELOPER, FREEWAY COMPANY (PART TIME)

FreeWay is a startup company focused on the development of mobile applications for freight using the software development methodology Scrum.

- Participated in the creation of the first project coding the main structure of it.
- Development of a mobile application using the Flutter framework and consuming
 information through GraphQL queries, where a CRUD was created for the cargo services
 flow in a freight transport application. In addition to this, by being a team lead, I actively
 participate in giving feedback to other developers by doing code reviews, pair coding or
 simply chatting to find the best possible solution.
- Helped to introduce new developers to the environment of the projects, creating solutions and managing a good internal code structure.
- I served as team lead of a mobile development team, actively using the Scrum methodology preparing Sprint planning, Sprint retrospectives as well as creating tickets for new features or issues.

Technologies implemented: Flutter, Graphql, Zeplin, GitHub, Git.

MAY. 2021 - NOV. 2022

FRONTEND DEVELOPER, HMH SISTEMAS SCHOOL

Software company specialized in web development using React.js and Vue.js

- Planned, designed, and developed 2+ software projects from zero to deploy using agile methodologies.
- Participated in the management of a medicine delivery application where I worked with the Google Maps Platform API creating Polylines, user interfaces and real-time tracking of the shipment. This implementing the GMaps API as well as Vue.js and Sass.
- Re-make UX-UI in point of sale application, this new experience was developed using Vue.js and SASS using the BEM methodology.
- Implemented reusable components in order to reduce the project development time.

Technologies implemented: HTML5, CSS, Sass, React.js, Vue.js (Options and Composition API), Buefy, Bootstrap, Gitlab, Git, i18n.

EDUCATION

2019 - 2023 - SOFTWARE ENGINEERING, SCHOOL OF TELEMATICS, UNIVERSITY OF COLIMA

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JS (ES6), Git (Github, Gitlab), Typescript, Vue.js (Vue 2, Vue3), React.js (Context API, Redux), Sass, Bulma, Scrum, Flutter, Figma, Bootstrap, AWS (IAM, Lambda, S3, CloudWatch, Simple Queue Service), NodeJS, GraphQL, Cypress, PostgreSQL, Vite, Vitest, Tailwind CSS, shadcn, Axios, Leaflet.js, TanStack Query, Nest.js, TypeORM.